<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sdmx.io e-learning library on sdmx.io e-learning</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/</link><description>Recent content in sdmx.io e-learning library on sdmx.io e-learning</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unit 01 SDMX data transmission formats primer</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/001-sdmx-data-transmission-formats/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/001-sdmx-data-transmission-formats/</guid><description>SDMX data transmission formats The SDMX standard has 12 different formats for transmitting statistical data:
Type Version of the standard Format Currency EDI SDMX 1.0 GESMES/TS EDIFACT data message current XML SDMX 1.0 / 2.0 SDMX-ML Generic (time-series) data message obsolete XML SDMX 1.0 / 2.0 SDMX-ML Compact (time-series) data message obsolete XML SDMX 1.0 / 2.0 SDMX-ML Utility (time-series) data message obsolete XML SDMX 1.0 / 2.0 SDMX-ML Cross-Sectional data message obsolete XML SDMX 2.</description></item><item><title>Unit 01 About structural metadata and 'metadata registries'</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/getting-start-running-in-docker/001-structural-metadata-and-metadata-registry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/getting-start-running-in-docker/001-structural-metadata-and-metadata-registry/</guid><description>What is a &amp;lsquo;metadata registry&amp;rsquo;? Wikipedia tells us that a metadata registry is a central location in an organisation where metadata definitions are stored and maintained in a controlled method.
A metadata registry can therefore be thought of as a database for metadata.
About &amp;lsquo;structural metadata&amp;rsquo; Fusion Metadata Registry focuses principally on structural metadata.
In SDMX, structural metadata are the Concepts, Codelists, Data Structure Definitions (DSDs) and other artefacts that together can be used for modelling statistical data domains.</description></item><item><title>Unit 02 SDMX XML data transmission formats</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/002-xml-formats/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/002-xml-formats/</guid><description>Introduction The XML data transmission format was introduced with SDMX 1.0 and is known as SDMX-ML data.
It provides a good balance between usability, human readability and transmission efficiency - particularly if compressed. These characteristics in addition to its early introduction have made XML the most widely used format.
Since SDMX 1.0, the standard has accumulated seven different variants of the XML data format.
In this unit we&amp;rsquo;ll look at the three most relevant:</description></item><item><title>Unit 02 What is FMR?</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/getting-start-running-in-docker/002-what-is-fmr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 18:36:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/getting-start-running-in-docker/002-what-is-fmr/</guid><description>FMR uses the SDMX 3.0 information model FMR 11 uses the SDMX 3.0 information model internally for storing and organising the structural metadata it holds.
We&amp;rsquo;ll look at the SDMX 3.0 information model in more detail in the next module, but for now the key point is that FMR 11 is able to natively work with the structures as defined in SDMX 3.0.
SDMX 2.1 structures are supported for backward compatibility where possible.</description></item><item><title>Unit 03 SDMX JSON data transmission formats</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/003-json-formats/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/003-json-formats/</guid><description>Introduction JSON was introduced as a transmission format for both structures and data as an addition to SDMX 2.1. Unlike XML there are only two versions of the data message.
In this unit we&amp;rsquo;ll look at the general principles of the JSON data message and note the differences between the two versions.
SDMX-JSON v1 data transmission message The SDMX-JSON v1 data message specification was added to SDMX 2.1 principally to satisfy the use case for data dissemination on the Internet where JSON is easier to use for websites and web data publication applications.</description></item><item><title>Unit 03 SDMX 3.0 information model fundamentals</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/getting-start-running-in-docker/003-sdmx30-information-model-fundamentals/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 12:30:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/getting-start-running-in-docker/003-sdmx30-information-model-fundamentals/</guid><description>In this unit In this unit we&amp;rsquo;ll take a high level look at the SDMX 3.0 information model that underpins Fusion Metadata Registry 11, why it&amp;rsquo;s important and which bits it&amp;rsquo;s worth knowing to help get started with FMR.
The SDMX 3.0 model overview The SDMX 3.0 information model has around 34 separate structures which can be used for modelling data domains, modelling data collection, data discovery and other purposes.</description></item><item><title>Unit 04 SDMX CSV data transmission formats</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/004-csv-formats/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/004-csv-formats/</guid><description>Introduction CSV was introduced as a transmission format for data only as an addition to SDMX 2.1 and was subsequently updated with the release of SDMX 3.0.
Like JSON, there are two distinct versions of the data message:
version 1 supports the SDMX 2.1 information model version 2 supports the SDMX 3.0 information model In this unit we&amp;rsquo;ll look at the general principles of the SDMX CSV data messages and note the differences between the two versions.</description></item><item><title>Unit 04 What is Docker</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/getting-start-running-in-docker/004-what-is-docker/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/getting-start-running-in-docker/004-what-is-docker/</guid><description>Skip this unit if you already understand the principles of Docker and containerisation.
In this unit In this lesson we&amp;rsquo;ll introduce just enough about Docker and the principles of &amp;lsquo;containerisation&amp;rsquo; in order to use it for running Fusion Metadata Registry.
What is Docker? Docker is a software platform for building and running applications in containers.
Containers are executable collections of software in which application code is packaged, along with its libraries and dependencies so that it can be run anywhere, whether it be on desktop, traditional IT, or the cloud.</description></item><item><title>Unit 05 EDI data transmission formats</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/005-edifact-format/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/005-edifact-format/</guid><description>Introduction CSV was introduced as a transmission format for data only as an addition to SDMX 2.1 and was subsequently updated with the release of SDMX 3.0.
Like JSON, there are two distinct versions of the data message:
version 1 supports the SDMX 2.1 information model version 2 supports the SDMX 3.0 information model In this unit we&amp;rsquo;ll look at the general principles of the SDMX CSV data messages and note the differences between the two versions.</description></item><item><title>Unit 05 Install and operate Docker Desktop</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/getting-start-running-in-docker/005-install-and-operate-docker-desktop/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/getting-start-running-in-docker/005-install-and-operate-docker-desktop/</guid><description>Skip this unit if you already understand how to use Docker Desktop.
In this unit In this unit we&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to install Docker Desktop and basic operations.
Get Docker Desktop The machine will need at least 4GB of memory.
On Windows Double-click Docker Desktop Installer.exe to run the installer. Download the installer from Docker Hub. It typically downloads to your Downloads folder, or you can run it from the recent downloads bar at the bottom of your web browser.</description></item><item><title>Unit 06 Create and run an FMR Docker container</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/getting-start-running-in-docker/006-run-fmr-docker-container/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/getting-start-running-in-docker/006-run-fmr-docker-container/</guid><description>In this unit In this final unit we&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to use Docker command line to pull the image for the latest FMR version, start a running container and begin working with FMR.
Start an FMR container from Docker command line Using Docker command line, execute the following commands:
Pull the latest FMR image from Docker Hub:
docker pull metadatatechnology/fmr-mysql:latest This could take a few minutes while layers that make up the image are downloaded from Docker Hub.</description></item><item><title>sdmx.io e-learning</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/_footer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/_footer/</guid><description>Copyright 2022 Bank for International Settlements. All rights reserved.</description></item><item><title>sdmx.io e-learning</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/_header/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/_header/</guid><description>e-learning</description></item></channel></rss>