<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SIO-2202 Data conversion fundamentals on sdmx.io e-learning</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/</link><description>Recent content in SIO-2202 Data conversion fundamentals on sdmx.io e-learning</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unit 01 SDMX data transmission formats primer</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/001-sdmx-data-transmission-formats/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/001-sdmx-data-transmission-formats/</guid><description>SDMX data transmission formats The SDMX standard has 12 different formats for transmitting statistical data:
Type Version of the standard Format Currency EDI SDMX 1.0 SDMX-EDI GESMES/TS EDIFACT data message current XML SDMX 1.0 / 2.0 SDMX-ML Generic (time-series) data message obsolete XML SDMX 1.0 / 2.0 SDMX-ML Compact (time-series) data message obsolete XML SDMX 1.0 / 2.0 SDMX-ML Utility (time-series) data message obsolete XML SDMX 1.0 / 2.0 SDMX-ML Cross-Sectional data message obsolete XML SDMX 2.</description></item><item><title>Unit 02 SDMX XML</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/002-xml-formats/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/002-xml-formats/</guid><description>Introduction The XML data transmission format was introduced with SDMX 1.0 and is known as SDMX-ML data.
It provides a good balance between usability, human readability and transmission efficiency - particularly if compressed. These characteristics in addition to its early introduction have made XML the most widely used format.
Since SDMX 1.0, the standard has accumulated seven different variants of the XML data format.
In this unit we&amp;rsquo;ll look at the three most relevant:</description></item><item><title>Unit 03 SDMX JSON</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/003-json-formats/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/003-json-formats/</guid><description>Introduction JSON was introduced as a transmission format for both structures and data as an addition to SDMX 2.1. Unlike XML there are only two versions of the data message.
In this unit we&amp;rsquo;ll look at the general principles of the JSON data message and note the differences between the two versions.
SDMX-JSON v1 data transmission message The SDMX-JSON v1 data message specification was added to SDMX 2.1 principally to satisfy the use case for data dissemination on the Internet where JSON is easier to use for websites and web data publication applications.</description></item><item><title>Unit 04 SDMX CSV</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/004-csv-formats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/004-csv-formats/</guid><description>Introduction CSV was introduced as a transmission format for data only as an addition to SDMX 2.1 and was subsequently updated with the release of SDMX 3.0.
Like JSON, there are two distinct versions of the data message:
version 1 supports the SDMX 2.1 information model version 2 supports the SDMX 3.0 information model In this unit we&amp;rsquo;ll look at the general principles of the SDMX CSV data messages and note the differences between the two versions.</description></item><item><title>Unit 05 SDMX EDI</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/005-edifact-format/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/005-edifact-format/</guid><description>Introduction SDMX-EDI is based on the EDI (Electronic Data Interchange) method for electronically communicating information between computer systems.
EDI originated in the 1970s and is characterised by a very terse text-based format for encoding the information. This terseness was originally needed due to the low communications bandwidths and processing power available. Over time, other formats such as XML became technically feasible as communications and computing improved, however EDI remains in use for the exchange of statistical data particularly in central banking.</description></item><item><title>Unit 07 Interactive data conversion using the FMR user interface</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/007-fmr-ui-convert/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/007-fmr-ui-convert/</guid><description>Introduction SDMX datasets can be converted interactively between transmission formats using the Convert Data function in FMR&amp;rsquo;s web user interface.
The interactive data conversion workflow Conversion of an SDMX dataset follows a defined worflow that starts with loading the data from either a file or a URL.
Load data flowchart LR
0((Convert Data
option
on menu )) --> A
A(Load data) --> B(Validate data)
style A fill:#f9f,stroke:#333,stroke-width:4px
B --> C{Map data?</description></item><item><title>Unit 08 Quick convert function</title><link>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/008-quick-convert/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://metadatatechnology.github.io/sdmxiolearn/tools/fmr/data-conversion-fundamentals/008-quick-convert/</guid><description>Introduction FMR&amp;rsquo;s quick convert function provides a quick way to interactively convert datasets in SDMX and FMR Excel formats to SDMX-ML 2.1 Structure Specific.
Drag or choose a file to convert flowchart LR
style A fill:#f9f,stroke:#333,stroke-width:4px
style B fill:#f9f,stroke:#333,stroke-width:4px
0((Convert Data
option
on menu )) --> A
0 --> B
A(Drag file) --> C(Automatic convert and download)
B(Choose file) --> C
C -..->|optional| D(View validation report)
Either drag a file onto the Quick Convert box, or click Choose a file and select from disk.</description></item></channel></rss>